<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Last Name in the Hat</title>
    <description>Last Name in the Hat is a small game development team working on creating Kuraz!</description>
    <link>http://lnith.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://lnith.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 19:09:26 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 19:09:26 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kickstarter Announcement</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0 auto&quot; src=&quot;/img/Kickstarter_Poster.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;JUNE 17TH&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thats right, we have a date for the Kickstarter! Despite life getting in and mucking everything up a bunch, we’re still pushing forward and are insanely excited to reach a point that we can confidently release the Kickstarter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re still hard at work at trying to finish an early alpha of the game that we could release for people to playtest during the Kickstarter campaign. The goal of this build will be demonstrating the main gameplay elements in the tactical portion of the game, cover, shields, flanking, and other such elements. Given this will be liable to change as we will continue fine-tuning the game, but the core-elements shall remain there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So tell your friends, family, and your dog about this Kickstarter, as we’ll be seeing you all very shortly!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://lnith.github.io/2015/06/03/Kickstarter-Annoucement/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lnith.github.io/2015/06/03/Kickstarter-Annoucement/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Slums to Skyscrapers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello all! This is Annamarie Mickey, the lead artist on the Last Name in a Hat team! Or head character designer. Or lead concept artist. Take your pick, I wear a lot of hats around these parts (pun intended).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was brought on the team sometime during the summer. It really only took one Skype call with Cody, our team leader, to pique my interest in the story of “Kuraz.” We’ve all seen our share of space games, but what I love about “Kuraz”—and what influenced the concepts and designs I’ve pursued with this game—are the people and society of Kuraz itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some incredible technology exists in this future galaxy. Terraforming, highly advanced weapons, space ships… and people with the money to buy and use it all. Most of those people, though, don’t live on Kuraz. And those that do sit up in high skyscrapers with beautiful, colorful glass domes that keep the dirt and grime of the planet out of sight and out of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0 auto&quot; src=&quot;/img/City_Fancy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Opulent skyscrapers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the rich entrepreneurs and corrupt corporations, our story buries itself deep into that gritty dust and dirt, and the people who have to be as tough as nails to live in it. While designing the characters you’ll meet over the course of the game, I realized that these people—the true heart of the planet—have barely glimpsed the technology that created the colony on Kuraz. Brief glimpses of ships in the sky heading towards the wealthy end of the city, failed corporate attempts to clean up the slums, bits and pieces of scavenged weapons… these are the only experiences of the future’s “incredible technology” for most Kuraz citizens. And it’s hardly impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of sight, out of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What sort of people are molded from such an environment? What sort of streets do they walk down? What kind of sky do they view every day? What is the view from the patched windows in their tiny apartments and houses nestled between warehouses and tucked tight in the slums, where gangs and mercenary groups have control of the undercity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0 auto&quot; src=&quot;/img/City_Slums.png&quot; alt=&quot;The slums&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what view are they missing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are a lot of the questions I asked myself while designing the world of Kuraz (both the planet and the story), and exploring them has been both challenging and a lot of fun. And as the Last Name in a Hat team brings the art, story, music, and gameplay together, I hope you’re as eager as I have been to explore “Kuraz”!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://lnith.github.io/2015/04/08/From-Slums-to-Skyscrapers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lnith.github.io/2015/04/08/From-Slums-to-Skyscrapers/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kuraz Story</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So last time on our devblog here we gave a quick overview of some of the key mechanics of &lt;i&gt;Kuraz&lt;/i&gt;. Today, we’re going to share just a set-up of the story you’ll be experiencing throughout the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;img src=&quot;/img/Kuraz_Planet_View.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kuraz from space&quot;&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0 auto&quot; src=&quot;/img/Kuraz_Planet_View.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kuraz from space&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Kuraz&lt;/i&gt; takes place several hundred years in the future on the game’s titular planet. Kuraz is ignored when the colonization rush happens due to being very inhospitable. The water on the planet is somewhat acidic and thusly there is very little vegetation (if any) on the planet. It is only when a group of colonists - seeking to live a life with literally zero government interference - use the planet as a chance to truly live out that dream. Without the funds to have the planet properly terraformed, these colonists make due with what resources they could scrape together. They discovered Kuraz’s subterranean water reservoirs, purified as it seeped through the planet’s soil (one of the few uses for Kuraz’s vast amounts of dirt and sand).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this discovery alone made Kuraz… not hospitable, perhaps, but livable. Over the course of three decades, Kuraz gains renown for the freedoms its inhabitants enjoyed, and that’s when corporations take interest. In the coming decades, several off-world corporations begin helping several corporations native to the planet grow, and generally improving the already good life on Kuraz. However, the drive for greater profits combined with the lack of any oversight, drives some corporations to begin ethically questionable practices. While only minor things at first (company script instead of money as an example) things quickly became much worse, ranging from crimes against humanity to the funding of pirates and smugglers in the nearby solar systems.With a number of corporations vying for power, waging small wars with their private armies, one corporation emerges as the “victor”, The Anderson Corporation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Anderson Corporation, initially formed on Kuraz, finds a large amount of off-world investors for it to get its operations started off. After the decline of ethical standards on Kuraz, The Anderson Corporation maintains good public relations by only practicing questionable ethics on opposing corporations rather than their own workers - a CEO assassination, bombing key facilities, things that crippled their opponents, but left the working man safe. With this dominance, Anderson begins delving into “criminal” activities, actively funding pirate and smuggling operations in the nearby solar systems. It’s after this that nearby planets who are members of Sol-Sys requested the federation take action. Sol-Sys is a federation of planets that formed after the initial colonization rush. The main purpose of this federation is to guarantee basic human rights since many planets are breeding grounds for all sorts of exploitation. In return for being a member and following the guidelines required, member’s interests would be protected as well. With the recent outbreak of piracy, Sol-Sys sends one of its best agents, a man by the codename “Dart”, to cripple the Anderson Corporation from the inside and avoid a full-scale war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this, is where our story begins.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://lnith.github.io/2015/03/15/Kuraz-Story-Set-Up/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lnith.github.io/2015/03/15/Kuraz-Story-Set-Up/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kuraz Introduction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the first developer blog post of Last Name in the Hat! This will be a weekly (maybe bi-weekly) blog keeping everyone up to date with the latest developments for our first title, “Kuraz”, a tactical turn-based RPG where you control a small army of elite mercenaries and soldiers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To explain the game a bit more, gameplay will consist of commanding a squad on a variety of different battlefields. You’ll maneuver your troops on a grid to utilize cover, flank the opposition, and ultimately overcome your foes. After you defeat your foes, you can use the resources gained from completing the mission to improve your army or hire more soldiers. And thats the very basics of the game, mind you the bare basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To go into more detail concerning the combat gameplay, each unit is equipped with a shield which is capable of stopping a few ranged attacks before it breaks and has to recharge. The way shields are set up, is they determine whether or not an object is moving at a high enough velocity that could damage the wearer. This allows the wearer to survive a bullet to the head, yet still be able to high-five his squadmate. Because of this, melee weapons have actually been making a resurgence as they can bypass the shields of their target. Additionally, our method of how effective cover is and whether or not someone is flanking another is a lot more math intensive than just using a simple ray to determine if there is cover in the way. We’ll go over the actual calculation in a future post, but suffice to say, based off of the angle you are attacking someone then determines how effective the cover they are behind will be. Lastly, every unit has a particular range their weapons excel at. Firing at enemies in this range confers a bonus to attacking, while firing outside of this range gives a malus. So its entirely possible for that guy with a pistol to snipe the sniper across the map… but hes probably better off taking cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The management aspect of our game is fairly straight forward as you might expect. You have a number of different unit types with varying attributes that lend themselves to certain play styles. Additionally, you are free to hire units as you see fit whether that is entirely snipers or tons of medics. With all of these units, they’ll need equipment, and there is a plethora of different items to customize to your playstyle. Maybe you’d prefer shields that can take an extra hit or two, but have to take an extra three turns to recharge after their battery is drained; Or perhaps, a shield that can recharge after only a turn or two, but can only stop two shots before its drained. One thing of note, is how these units gain experience. Each time a unit returns from combat, they will gain a certain amount of experience based off of how difficult the mission was. For hero units (like the main protagonist) their experience is their own. However, for units like your average assault trooper, the collective experience gained by all assaults on the mission will be added to the class as a whole. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thats pretty much the jist of Kuraz. We’ll continue updating this devblog with more info (both technical and progress wise) as we continue to develop the game over the coming months. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 04:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://lnith.github.io/2015/02/26/Kuraz-Introduction/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lnith.github.io/2015/02/26/Kuraz-Introduction/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
